And I wouldn’t blame him.
But once this is all mine,
he will still be a
thorn in my side.
And his mother falling
into line won’t help.
No.
He’s going to require
a far stronger hand.
It’s not a matter of if.
Simply put, the question
becomes do I take care
of Telemachus now, or do
I take care of him later?
It’s like my father used to say.
Only a fool leaves
today’s jobs until tomorrow.
Well, Antinous is no fool.
Neither will this loyal dog.
No.
This loyal dog will be
ready for you, Antinous.
My reward...
Speak to me.
Odysseus!
I need to get my rewards!
What?
What are you doing?
My rewards, my gold!
They’re speaking to me!
- Not when we’re so close!
- Yes!
No! Just pass the rocks,
and we’re nearly home!
They speak to me!
Polites!
Wake up!
Take this beeswax!
Put it in your ears!
We must block their song!
We must block
the siren’s song!
Block it!
We cannot hear them!
We’ve got to stay clear of them!
We’ve got to stay away!
Steady on the course...
until we can’t hear them!
Steer away...
Steer away.
That song...
Oh...
I want to hear that song.
Odysseus!
- That song...
- Odysseus!
Odysseus!
Don’t listen to them!
Here!
No, the wax!
The wax!
The song...
Odysseus! We’re leaving!
We’re getting out of here!
I want to hear that song.
They know nothing but death!
- They want to help us.
- They do not.
- They do want to help us.
- They don’t want to help us.
- Polites...
- Think of your family!
- Polites, they want to help us.
- No, no, no!
They will not!
Polites, they know
how to get home.
We’ve come this far!
- Polites...
- We’ve come this far!
- They only know death!
- They have wisdom!
They only know death!
Their song is wisdom.
Hey! Snap out of it!
They want to help us.
They know what
lies beneath the waves.
I must hear this song.
Song of the sirens.
What a beautiful song.
Huh.
They want to help us get home.
They do.
They have knowledge.
Polites, they have wisdom.
- Odysseus...
- Their beautiful song.
I must hear it.
Odysseus, they know
nothing but death.
They have knowledge.
They know nothing but death.
Think of home.
The song.
No, Polites, we
must steer towards them.
Polites, they want to help us!
No, they don’t!
Yes!
Their song!
I want to hear their song...
Please, Polites.
They sing for me!
Odysseus!
Hear me, Odysseus!
You must not listen
to them, Odysseus!
I can only hear their song.
Odysseus!
No!
You can’t hear me
over their song!
Odysseus!
You will die if you don’t
make it past these rocks!
And if you cannot hear me,
I cannot help you!
I cannot help you.
Odysseus!
Odysseus, no!
Polites, we must
steer away from the rocks.
Please steer away from them.
We must get to Ithaca.
They will give us
a hero’s welcome.
A king’s welcome.
Damn the sirens.
And damn these seas, too.
Polites, please forgive me.
You have saved
both of our lives.
It was an honor, my king.
But now our course is set.
You are almost home.
And that is your reward.
But mind, my king,
my reward is treasure.
You must listen to me.
You don’t understand.
No, no, no, I do understand.
You have a gift from the gods.
And Ithaca, now
that is your reward.
Now I am in pursuit of mine.
You said, your words.
What do you mean?
Gifts for good men.
Did you not?
Please, you do not understand.
No, I do understand. It’s you
that doesn’t understand.
I saw Athena
herself give it to you.
- I saw her.
- No, no.
A gift from the gods. Reward.
No, it’s not a gift.
- Oh, it’s not a gift?
- No, it’s not.
I see it.
I see, clever Polites,
loyal Polites,
worthy of scars Polites,
but not worthy of a gift
from the gods, is that it?
Please listen to me.
Exactly like Troy, is it?
Exactly like Troy.
I am going to take
what is owed to me.
For good men.
No, no, do not take that.
Do not take that!
Bring it back.
You do not understand.
- No, stop.
- I do understand.
Stop!
Polites, please, please.
My King, I am only opening this
because this is
what is owed to me.
- No.
- Yes.
Athena.
Athena, please.
Perhaps the fates are more
generous than we thought.
Athena.
Even the winds had mercy
on you and brought you home.
Reward. Reward.
Great Odysseus finally returned
to the shores of Ithaca.
Ithaca.
Telemachus...
Penelope!
The great Odysseus...
At the end of his ropes.
No.
Not yet.
Not quite.
Look.
There, Your Majesty.
Your people are in panic.
Perhaps there is no more
glory left for you here.
Penelope and Telemachus
are doing all they can.
But your city is
being taken by force.
My world burns.
And the gods abandon me
with my hands tied.
I can offer no more aid,
and you know this.
By breathing wind
into your sails,
strategizing your
boat as a weapon,
and giving you a bag of wind,
your three gifts have been used.
But great goddess,
I never opened the bag of winds.
It was Polites.
Polites opened the bag of winds.
Not I.
A wrinkle.
Perhaps it is enough
for the gods to allow me
to aid you one last
time on your journey.
I have one boon.
One gift left.
I just pray I don’t
have to use it.
Yes, but you cannot
just go home, Odysseus.
Not anymore.
The people of Ithaca,
they are a mob.
They run through the
streets hungry for blood.
They would have yours.
You will not make it past them.
You will not even make it
to your front door.
And if you did, the suitors
would be waiting for you.
In disguise.
In disguise to hide
my face in my own kingdom.
I shall dress as a
wandering beggar
and learn how things stand.
What will you do,
Great Odysseus?
I will defend my home.
My family.
I must stop this
before it’s too late.
Or even if it’s as you say,
there’s no glory
left for either of us.
Finish the game, Odysseus.
And finish it well.
For not all gods
have abandoned you.
And Poseidon still
thirsts for revenge.
We must do something, Mother.
No.
I will not let them kill you.
You must get
control of the city.
We will wait until
your father returns.
Rioting!
Looting and violence,
and you want to wait for
Odysseus to return?
Do you still think
you’ll have a kingdom by then?
Without a king,
my queen,
the city succumbs to
its more primal urges.
I will take your hand
and the crown with it.
And all will be well
when King Antinous reigns.
It is time, my lord.
Time enough indeed
for the final challenge.
No more games, loyal widow.
Being king is no game.
And only the worthy
wear our crown
and complete this final task.
Only our king can fire an
arrow through those axe blades.
And only our king has done it.
So are you our king, Antinous?
Or does Odysseus, even in
his absence, carry the crown?
You’re not worth of such
a great feat!
I challenge you for
my Father’s kingdom!
Snake in the grass!
Stay in your place, pup!
Telemachus!
But if I must, I will
teach you to keep your place!
The crown will never be yours!
Snake in the grass!
Interloper! Villain!
Yes, I am.
And much worse.
Begging your apologies.
I was merely returning
the young man his sword.
I...
I would like to ask the young
lady if I may compete.
Another suitor?
With the queen’s
permission, of course.
We need no more suitors!
I will--
The courtesy of
my husband’s house
is much diminished
as of late.
You may compete.
And I pray you might
restore what has been lost.
Only Odysseus can put an
arrow through those axe blades.
So, let’s see how good you are.
Good.
Clever.
Clever is better than good.
It’s a farce!
He can’t even keep the
arrow straight, my queen.
Best keep your eye
on the target, old man.
So, only Odysseus
himself can make this shot.
And I must be Odysseus.
But Odysseus is dead!
- No!
- Father!
You have overstayed your
welcome in my house too long!
Antinous!
You can leave on
your own accord.
Never!
This kingdom is mine!
Or you can go another way!
Death is too good for you.
Watch your tongue!
Or we will take it from you.
No!
My gods!
Help me!
Have mercy on me!
Here I am, monster!
I’ll slaughter you and
your family,
and the whole of Ithaca!
No! No!
Here I am! Here I am!
I’m the one you want!
Take me! Take me!
Father!
Odysseus?
Odysseus!
No!
What did he say to you, son?
Tell me!
Tell me quickly!
What were his
final words to you?
I don’t understand!
Telemachus...
What were his final words?
He said, third gift.
Third gift?
And then...
And then nothing more.
So clever.
The king of Ithaca.
Clever to his last.
Oh, goddess Athena.
My love.
You have suffered
enough these past many days.
But the game’s over.
Odysseus...
Wins.
What do you mean?
He didn’t win.
He’s dead.
He’s gone!
Do not be troubled,
son of Odysseus.
Once again, your
father’s glory honors me.
With his final breath,
your husband requested his
last wish.
May I grant it?
Yes.
Yes, please.
Clever is indeed
greater than good.
- Father!
- He’s alive!
Goddess Athena, thank you.
It was your husband
who outsmarted death.
I am glad to see
you all reunited.
My son...
Oh, my son.
I was gone.
The goddess.
Athena has granted me
my third wish.
My father more clever
than the gods themselves.
The river Styx can wait...
But a moment longer.
Oh...
You took your time, old man.
The wind.
The wind was against me.
I have heard such stories.
You seem as if from a dream.
Are you really here?
Or are the gods
still playing games.
I have not the strength
for their sport any longer.
Nor do I.
Nor do I, my queen.
King of Ithaca, why have
you returned to this place?
I have but one goal.
One destination.
Not Ithaca, not this house,
not the crown was my goal.
I care not for the seas
or the skies.
I sought no monsters, nor gods.
I only sought you.
Only you.
You... You were the
safe harbor I fought
so desperately to get home to.
And home you will stay.
Yes, I will.
Home.
The only journey
worth the fight.
Home.
Home at last.